but the most useful thing we can craft with some more steel is a charcoal pile igniter
to use it, we first have to dig a huge hole
with some bricks on the bottom
we fill that hole with logs
and after covering all of the wood with dirt
we put an new machinery on top of it
and it was then that something weird happened
a wild giant brick (?) appeared
maybe we have touched too much grass
and this is the quest book telling us to go touch bricks
and the first thing we can do of those bronze plated bricks
is a multiblock steam alloy smelter
since that thing will eat a lot of steam
we start by using it to produce a new alloy we only dreamed of, stronze
sturdy as steel and valuable as bronze
this materials is indeed great both for pipes and for tools
we can also use the extra space in our new machine to alloy some clay compound
that is the only material enough lightweight and sturdy to make our new hydraulic parts
but of course the first thing we have to do
is break many tools in order to work the dozens of stacks of metal ingots
required to make some hydraulic motors
with those new hydraulic parts
we can craft to Carpenter
which will allow us to do more advanced stuff with wood
such as plating it
and with plated wood
we can make a woodcutter
and that machine doesn't just cut wood
it also grows it with the power of steam
after building it
we set it up to cultivate cactus
which we can use to feed our new maximum sized boiler
with all of that steam
we can now power some bigger machinery
the first one is going to be the Steam Conformer
which is an improved version of the Forge Hammer
which allow for hammering stuff into of various shapes
making it more versatile than a forge hammer but not as efficient as an extruder
next we build a steam blender
that mixer will allow us to mix the malleability of bronze with the sturdiness of steel
making breel
which must not be confused with stronze
and by using both of those materials
we can build a better blast furnace
but this one works in a slight different way
after feeding it materials
it will turn on but it won't work
that is because it will turn steam input into time progress
so we add a steam input pipe
and now we see how nicely it works with just a small steel pipe worth of steam
it works so nicely that it quickly used up all of our carbon fuel
to fix that, we rooted some cactus into the new infernal coke oven
this will make cactus charcoal
which we then pass again inside another infernal coke oven to make cactus coke
which we can now feed to our blast furnace
those two can also keep up with our boiler
and they didn't even reach their final speed yet
but if we want to make steel even faster
we can use a hotter kind of steam
we can achieve that by fusing normal steam with creosote oil
making superheated steam
we pump that into our blast furnace
and now we can make instant steel
with all of that steel we can build an extractinator
then we also built some extra machines to support it
it all starts from a steam cobbler
which will make cobblestone from lava water interaction
cobblestone is then smashed down into gravel
next, it is mixed to water, forming a sluice which is finally feed to our extractinator
here, with the power of super heated steam
we can extract all sorts of goodies out of watered stone
next, we filter those goodies and work the best stuff into ingots
and thus, with a couple more of machines
we have an unlimited source of bronze, iron and steel
which we bring right into our base
however, as you'd probably expect
we quickly run out of steam
luckily, by extracting (?) obsidian sluice we can obtain silver
and I think we all know where this is going
into a new mega pressure solar boiler
as you can see
it is happily boiling 100,000 liters of steam per second
with all of that steam
we can now work on crafting a steam manufacturer
that took quite a lot of resources and many crafting steps
but we managed to complete it
since once again we tried to optimize space
we can admire it in all of its glory from the NEI preview
the first usage we have for this machine is crafting steel turbines
with those we can upgrade our pumps to fluid regulators
which will allow us to control the flow of a jet of steam in it
thus allowing us to pipelessly connect our machines
and this will also allow us to use the whole universe as our steam tank
giving us all the room for buffering energy we could possibly need
now that we have upgraded our main machines with that new solution
we can also start looking for an even more fused kind of steam
supercritical steam
the easiest way to obtain it would be to add more creosote into our already superheated steam
a cheaper way is to boil water using lava
but that requires a compact hyper pressure reactor
which isn't too easy to craft
the only option left is to offer our compressed cactus coke to the Cactai gods in the Cactai pantheon
so we collect the leftover cactus we have been stocking
compress those a couple of times
and then bring that expensive block of super compressed cactus to the new shrine we just built
now the cacti deities will reward us with a lot of supercritical steam
with that acquired
we can move on to the next task
making a new machine
and this one doesn't really look like something we can craft by hand
so we start working on making more stuff passively
so, after making some more mess to passively produce all the basic materials
we make some more mess to passively make all kinds of plates
and it was then that we run into an issue
if we don't want to automate to crafting table with a good stock of tools
we need a couple of assemblers
and those are annoying and expensive
but since there is no other reliable way
we start mass producing every kind of part we can
then, after manually crafting our first assembler
we set up some hydraulic regulators to keep it stocked with the materials needed for our super compressor
and after enough time
we manage to get everything we needed
we fill our inventory with that stuff
and we proceed into building the new machine
and after realizing our inventory is small and we do not like walking
we take the whole drawer with us
and after completing the main structure
adding buses, hatches and pipeless power
we turn it on to compress steam into solid form
this new material will allow us to craft the most advanced technology we could only dream of in gaseous steam age
for example
we can make screws so lightweight that will be able to lift up not only a couple of gold rings
but also the people attached to those rings
now we can also access the Jetstream wireless hatches
and build some new giant mega blocks
but what we really are after is the more advanced hydraulic Jetstream Enchanted technology
however, those parts require some peculiar gems and rubber
so we quickly grab the material to craft some more automation
and automate the passive production for those things too
and after building some more spaghetti automation
we managed to obtain our gems
as for the rubber
we automated it all the way up to passive fluid regulators
with that, we can easily craft some of the advanced hydraulics parts
but before using those
we shall pay tribute of a quintuple compressed cactus coke to the cacti deities
so that the supercritical steam charm will light our path
and the next thing on our path is the infinite creation given by the perfect steam progenitor
at first that looks like a challenging thing to build
but thanks to our out of control passive restocking
we already have most of the parts required ready
and after crafting a bunch of extra parts
we are finally ready to assemble the machine of our dreams
and there it is
in all of its glory
but that was just one more step towards our final destination
and crafting the ultimate machine requires quite a bunch of materials
without getting too scared
we start working towards a bigger ore processing plant
and while all of that stuff is being passively crafted
we can work on something powerful enough to keep up with the demands of our ultimate construction
a steampunk Schrodinger's cat
that will act both as a spinning device and a multi dimensional linking device at once
and while crafting it took almost no time at all
finding its favorite food, anti money, took basically forever
next, after spending a lot of time time alternating between idling and looking around
we managed to craft the last part of the machine of our dreams
and with that, we have completed our steam tier into dimensional teleportation device
but the real reward here is the alien technology that will allow us to dig caves way faster than we could ever imagine
能用更多钢做出来的好东西，就是木炭堆点火器
要用它，首先得挖一个大坑
坑底垫上一些砖块
然后把原木塞满这个坑
再用泥土把原木全部盖住之后
我们把新机器放在最上面
就在那时，怪事发生了
一棵野生的（砖树？）出现了
也许是因为我们摸太多的草了
这是任务书在叫我们去摸砖头
而这批青铜镀层砖能做的第一件东西
就是多方块蒸汽合金冶炼炉
因为这玩意儿特别吃蒸汽
我们先用它来生产一种梦寐以求的新合金：stronze（无官方译名）
像钢一样结实，像青铜一样值钱
这种材料做管道和工具都非常好用
我们还可以利用新机器里多出来的空间，顺便合成一些黏土化合物
这是唯一一种又轻又结实、足以制作新液压部件的材料
但当然，首先要做的是
先折断一堆工具，去处理几十组金属锭
这些都是做液压马达需要的材料
有了这些新的液压部件
我们就能做出木工机
它能让我们对木材进行更高级的加工
比如给木头加覆层
而有了覆层木材
我们就能造出伐木机
这台机器不只是砍树
它还能靠蒸汽之力把树种出来
造好之后
我们把它设置成种仙人掌
用来给我们新建的最大号锅炉供燃料
有了这么多蒸汽
我们现在就能驱动更大的机器了
第一台是蒸汽成型机
它是锻造锤的改进版
可以把材料锤成各种形状
比锻造锤更通用，但效率又不如挤压机
接着我们造了一台蒸汽搅拌机
这台搅拌机能把青铜的延展性和钢的坚固性混在一起
做出 breel
可别把它和 stronze 搞混了
有了这两种材料
我们就能造出更好的高炉
不过这一台的工作方式略有不同
喂入材料后
它会启动，但并不会立刻工作
因为它会把蒸汽输入转换成时间进度
所以我们接上了一根蒸汽输入管
现在就能看到，只靠一根小钢管级别的蒸汽，它也能运转得很好
它效率好到很快就把我们的碳燃料全吃光了
为了解决这个问题，我们把一些仙人掌扔进新的地狱焦炉
先烧成仙人掌木炭
再送进另一台地狱焦炉里继续烧成仙人掌焦炭
现在就能拿去喂高炉了
这两台机器也能跟上锅炉的消耗
而且它们甚至还没跑到最终速度
但如果想让炼钢更快
我们还可以用更热的蒸汽
只要把普通蒸汽和杂酚油融合即可
得到过热蒸汽
把它泵进高炉
现在我们就能瞬间炼钢
有了这些钢，我们可以造一台提取机
然后又补了一些配套机器来支援它
整套流程从蒸汽造石机开始
它会利用熔岩与水的反应生成圆石
圆石接着被粉碎成砂砾
再和水混合成矿浆，最后送进提取机
在这里，借助过热蒸汽的力量
我们可以从这些湿润石料里提取出各种好东西
接着把这些产物过滤，再把最有价值的部分加工成锭
于是，再补上几台机器后
我们就拥有了无限的青铜、铁和钢来源
并把它们直接送回基地
不过，正如你可能猜到的
我们的蒸汽很快就不够用了
好在通过提取（？）黑曜石矿浆，我们可以拿到银
我想大家都知道接下来会发生什么
那就是一台新的巨型高压太阳能锅炉
如你所见
它正在愉快地每秒烧出 100,000 升蒸汽
有了这么多蒸汽
我们现在可以开始做蒸汽制造机了
这需要不少资源和很多合成步骤
但我们还是把它搞定了
由于我们又一次试图节省空间
它的全貌就只能在 NEI 预览里欣赏了
这台机器的第一个用途是制作钢涡轮
有了它们，我们可以把泵升级成流体调节器
这样就能控制其中喷射蒸汽的流量
从而让机器实现无管道连接
这还意味着我们可以把整个宇宙当作蒸汽储罐
给我们几乎无限的缓冲空间来储存所需能量
现在主力机器都完成了这套升级
我们也可以开始追求更进一步融合的蒸汽
也就是超临界蒸汽
最简单的获取方式，是在现有过热蒸汽里继续加入更多杂酚油
更便宜的方法是用熔岩烧水
但那需要一个紧凑型超压反应堆
而那东西并不好做
剩下唯一的办法，就是把压缩仙人掌焦炭献给仙人掌万神殿里的仙人掌诸神
于是我们把之前囤着的仙人掌余料全都收集起来
连压好几轮
再把这块昂贵的超压缩仙人掌，搬到刚建好的新神龛里
现在仙人掌神明就会奖励我们大量超临界蒸汽
有了这玩意儿
我们就能推进到下一个任务
也就是做一台新机器
而这东西看起来可不像能手搓出来的
所以我们开始继续扩展被动生产
于是，在又搭出一堆混乱产线来被动生产基础材料之后
我们又搭了一堆更乱的线来被动生产各种板材
就在这时，我们遇到了一个问题
如果不想给自动合成台塞上一大堆工具来自动化
那就得做几台组装机
而这东西又麻烦又贵
但既然没有别的靠谱方案
我们只好开始量产所有能量产的部件
然后，在手工搓出第一台组装机之后
我们布置了一些液压调节器，让它持续补充超级压缩机所需的材料
等了足够久之后
我们总算凑齐了所有需要的东西
我们把背包装满这些材料
然后开始搭建新机器
但很快就意识到背包太小，而且我们也不想来回跑腿
于是直接把整柜子搬了过来
完成主体结构后
再接上总线、仓口和无管道供能
我们启动它，把蒸汽压缩成固态
这种新材料能让我们做出在这个离谱蒸汽时代里曾经只敢想的高级技术
比如
我们可以做出轻到夸张的螺丝，不仅能托起几枚金戒指
还能把挂在戒指上的人一并托起来
现在我们也能用上 Jetstream 无线舱口
并建造一些新的巨型多方块
但我们真正追求的是更高级的液压 Jetstream 附魔技术
不过这些部件需要一些特殊宝石和橡胶
所以我们赶紧去凑材料，继续加自动化
把这些资源也做成被动产线
又堆了一堆意面式自动化之后
我们总算拿到了宝石
至于橡胶
我们一路自动化到了可被动生产流体调节器的程度
这样一来，先进液压部件就能轻松做出来
但在动用这些之前
我们得向仙人掌诸神献上一块五重压缩仙人掌焦炭
让超临界蒸汽的护佑照亮前路
而前方等待我们的，是完美蒸汽始祖赐予的无限造物
一开始这看起来很有挑战性
但多亏我们几乎失控的被动补货系统
所需的大部分部件其实都已经备好了
再补做一批额外零件之后
我们终于可以组装梦想之机了
它就在这
光彩全开
但这还只是通往终点的又一步
而打造终极机器还需要海量材料
别慌
我们先着手建设更大的矿石处理产线
而在这些东西被动生产的同时
我们还可以去做一件足以满足终极建造需求的强力设备
蒸汽朋克版薛定谔之猫
它会同时充当旋转装置和多维链接装置
制作它本身几乎没花多少时间
反而是找它最爱吃的食物 antimony，花了几乎一整辈子
接下来，在长时间挂机和到处搜寻之间来回切换之后
我们终于做出了梦想之机的最后一个部件
至此，我们完成了蒸汽时代的维度传送装置
但真正的奖励，是外星科技带来的挖矿速度，快到超出想象